### Contact

exageradonome@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ josevaldirjunior (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

Culinary Skills Pastry Catering

#### Certifications

CS50x Computer Science
IBM Python Basics for Data Science

# Jose Junior

Pastry Chef at Shelbourne Social restaurant Greater Dublin

# Summary

Experience Chef de Partie, Pastry and Sushi Chef with 10 years experience in both teaching and preparing/presenting food in Ireland and Brazil. Currently Pastry Chef in Rustic by Dylan McGrath and looking to expand my skill set in Dublin. Available to work immediately.

# Experience

Shelbourne Social restaurant
Pastry Chef
November 2019 - March 2020 (5 months)
County Dublin, Ireland

Pastry chef responsible for bread section baking sourdough bread, focaccia, bao bun, burger bun and flatbreads and dessert as all kind of financiers, glaze cakes, puddings, soft serve ice creams, mousses, cheesecakes, temper dark, white and milk chocolates.

- Prepare pastry, dessert and biscuit products for 3 different menus and delivery
- Participate in an ongoing way in the development of new products and baking techniques and to play an active role in the product development and food forum
- Plan and prepare quantities and preparation in advance to ensure sufficient and timely deliveries to all shops and outlets
- Maintain flexibility in day to day activities to ensure customers orders can be accommodated
- Control the use of ingredients, minimise waste of ingredients and finished products and to maintain the food cost at the agreed level

- Use the recipe centre for every dish prepared; to ensure correct product quality and consistency, and quantities of each dish are produced.
- Comply with all HACCP and hygiene requirements to ensure high standards of hygiene and food safety at all times.
- Work with the kitchen team in ensuring good standards of cleanliness, housekeeping and maintenance are maintained
- Complete all daily paperwork and participate in the routine reviews of these records and results (e.g. Daily sheets, Orders, waste records, food cost, HACCP records etc.)
- Attend kitchen meetings with input and ideas
- Work together with the Pastry team, and the rest of the kitchen team to maintain a high level of morale

Fade Street Social - Restaurant - GastroBar - Cocktail Bar Chef di part April 2018 - November 2019 (1 year 8 months)

7 pm 2010 Provonibol 2010 (1 your o monuto)

County Dublin, Ireland

Chef di Partie on the Tapas restaurant, maintaining flexibility in day to day activities to ensure customers orders can be accommodated and fast serving with a high quality and dish presentation.

- Participate in an ongoing way in the development of new products and techniques and to play an active role in the product development.
- Plan and prepare quantities and preparation in advance to ensure sufficient and timely deliverie in a busy service.
- Control the use of ingredients, minimise waste of ingredients and finished products and to maintain the food cost at the agreed level
- Use the recipe centre for every dish prepared; to ensure correct product quality and consistency, and quantities of each dish are produced.

- Comply with all HACCP and hygiene requirements to ensure high standards of hygiene and food safety at all times.
- Work with the kitchen team in ensuring good standards of cleanliness, housekeeping and maintenance are maintained
- Complete all daily paperwork and participate in the routine reviews of these records and results (e.g. Daily sheets, Orders, waste records, food cost, HACCP records etc.)
- Attend kitchen meetings with input and ideas

Rustic Stone by Dylan McGrath Chef de Partie / Pastry Chef April 2017 - April 2018 (1 year 1 month)

County Dublin, Ireland

Pastry Chef responsible for seven different desserts including ice creams and sorbets, donuts, cakes, brulees, panna cotta, mousse, flan, cheesecake and Mochi

Prepare pastry, dessert and biscuit products to the standard of The Butler's Pantry

Participate in an ongoing way in the development of new products and baking techniques and to play an active role in the product development and food forum

Plan and prepare quantities and preparation in advance to ensure sufficient and timely deliveries to all shops and outlets

Maintain flexibility in day to day activities to ensure customers orders can be accommodated

Control the use of ingredients, minimise waste of ingredients and finished products and to maintain the food cost at the agreed level.

Use the recipe centre for every dish prepared; to ensure correct product quality and consistency, and quantities of each dish are produced.

Comply with all HACCP and hygiene requirements to ensure high standards of hygiene and food safety at all times.

Work with the kitchen team in ensuring good standards of cleanliness, housekeeping and maintenance are maintained Complete all daily paperwork and participate in the routine reviews of these records and results (e.g. Daily sheets, Orders, waste records, food cost, HACCP records etc.)

Attend kitchen meetings with input and ideas

Work together with the Pastry team, and the rest of the kitchen team to maintain a high level of morale

Self Employed
Sushi Chef Self-Employed
April 2015 - January 2017 (1 year 10 months)
County Dublin, Ireland

Self employed Sushi Chef catering for parties and events in Dublin Prepare the highest quality sushi rolls/bowls consistently and effectively for parties and events

Maintain kitchen, cooking area, sushi counters, kitchen equipment and food storage areas clean, sanitary and organized

Handle, store, label, and rotate foods properly and in accordance with public health safety, state and local laws. Follows Everclean Best Practices for food handling and storage

Kibo Bar E Restaurante Chef de Partie January 2014 - October 2014 (10 months) Brazil

Japanese Restaurant

Ensure all catering & wholesale orders are completed on time

Ensure preparation of all food

Assist with new menu items as necessary

Ensure all food preparation meets HACCP standards

Prepare and present high quality food

Supervise staff

Keep all working areas clean and tidy and ensure no cross contamination
Assist in positive outcomes from guest queries in a timely and efficient manner
Ensure food stuffs are of a good quality and stored correctly
Contribute to controlling costs, improving gross profit margins, and other
departmental and financial targets

Assist Head Chef/Sous Chef in the training of all staff in compliance of company procedures

Report maintenance, hygiene and hazard issue

The Sushi Club
Teaching Instructor Sushi Basico
February 2013 - August 2013 (7 months)
Brazil

National School of Oriental Cooking
Teaching demonstration and hands on cookery lessons
Kitchen Management
Working with team to ensure high customer service standards
Running corporate and external cookery lessons & events
Motivating and Training Staff

Sabara Bakery
Pastry Chef
January 2009 - January 2012 (3 years 1 month)
Brazil

Managing excellence in health and hygiene standards

Ensuring the customer experience is always positive
Responsible for directing all daily activities of the pastry section
Maintaining and delivering the highest standards on a daily basis
Helping lead and motivate the junior kitchen staff
Developing and managing all pastry/bread related items
Liaising with the café and catering managers to ensure that all customer expectations are met

Work with managers and staff to ensure all pastry and bread products are presented appropriately Work with Café staff and management to ensure that portion control is adhered to

Presenting a clean, neat and organised environment for customers

## Education

Sushi Club

Diploma , Japanise Cuisine · (2012 - 2012)

Auguste Escoffier School of Culinary Arts

Bachelor's degree, Culinary Arts/Chef Training (2016 - 2018)